Nice, Babs.
They're bagels actually.
Can you not look at me like that?
I'm your his sister.
Oh, yeah.
Sorry.
Oh, I feel Darth Baker is close by.
What do you think, Prue Baker?
Yeah, you could be right.
Yeah.
I shouldn't have taken the stairs.
I'm knackered.
Too many lemon drizzles, mate.
Oh, you just burnt my pie.
It's fine.
It's a little on the dark side.
Oh, I think my fruit sponge is ready.
Anyone?
Nah.
I think you'll be eating that flan solo.
Welcome to the Great.
British Bake.
Off.
No, you look like Billie Eilish's grandmother.
You look about for.
When I came in, I could see the edges of the tent.
It's almost here.
I am just a few steps away.
I feel as though I've fallen down a rabbit hole, and the Mad Hatter is going to come running around the corner.
I cannot wait to walk into that tent, feel what it's like to be one of those people.
I've never wanted to be in a tent so bad before.
From across Britain, thousands of the best home bakers applied.
Good luck.
But just 12 have made it.
I've always wanted to apply, but I never had the courage to actually do it this year.
I thought I'd give it a try.
And I'm here.
I work in a supermarket behind the checkouts.
This is the biggest thing I've ever done.
Things like this don't happen to me.
You just want to cry because you cannot believe this is real.
Over the next ten weeks.
It is going.
In.
They'll face 30 brand new challenges designed to put every bit of their baking ability to the test.
I've done baking for quite a while.
I feel maybe I'm sort of good at this.
We're about to find out how good for me, so maybe I'm terrible.
My partner said, fake it until you make it.
The stress is real, and that's what I'm doing.
Everything they make will be judged by Prue Leith.
It is utterly delicious.
And Paul Hollywood.
I'm intrigued to see if Paul's eyes are as blue as people say in real life.
Like a white walker or something.
Are they?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Look into your soul.
They'll start with astounding cakes.
Come on.
Oh, my.
A batch of Scrumptuous signature sandwiches.
Oh my God.
It's gone all crumbly.
Oh.
A classic American cake.
Yeah.
That'll catch some red handed.
It's gonna high five you.
But I've seen your palms.
Good luck.
Can't stop, can't stop.
And a showstopping home bake.
Oh.
What?
It's okay, it's okay.
It landed the right side up.
Yes.
That'll expose any shaky foundations.
I'm so worried.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Boom!
After two years away in Essex, we've pitched our tent back in the beautiful grounds of Welford Park.
And our fresh crop of bakers are about to face three cake based challenges, after which one of them will be crowned Star Baker and one will have to leave the competition.
Hello, bakers.
Welcome to the tent.
And it's time for your first ever signature challenge.
Today, the judges would love you to make a batch of 12 identical mini sandwich cakes.
Yeah.
You know, like Battenberg in a panini, Vicky sponge on sourdough loaf and a tuna melt.
I think that would be a cake sandwich.
They're looking for sandwich cakes.
Oh, good.
Cos they sounded rank.
They did sound.
The shape and flavours are entirely up to you, and you can use any sponge you like.
You have one hour.
What
sandwich?
Between two half hours.
You have two hours.
You got two hours on your mark.
Get set.
Bake.
Ooh,
quite. Little bit stress.
I'm not gonna lie.
I just hope that today will go okay.
Doesn't feel real yet.
Two hours.
It's not a long time to make 12 sandwich cakes.
I didn't feel great this morning.
Really nervous.
It's crazy because you're just making a cake.
And it's something you do all the time.
My sandwich cakes.
This looks like quite a simple challenge, but what we're really looking for is a bit of originality.
They could choose any sponge they want, but we want it to be small, packed with the flavour full of their personality.
It's the first time the bakers are going to show us what they can bake, so this is really important.
We want to see their skills.
They need to be absolutely identical.
Absolutely delicious.
Perfect sandwich.
Cake is what we want.
Good morning.
Rebs.
Hello, Rebs.
Good morning.
Right.
Tell us all about your mini sandwich cake.
I'm making hazelnut mocha latte.
Mini sandwich cakes because I used to work as a barista.
And it's the drink my boyfriend used to come in and order all the time when he was trying to chat me up.
So you're approaching this like a barista.
In a way.
These two are going to be absolutely pumped.
The amount of coffees going in it, hopefully.
Rebs from County Antrim in Northern Ireland has been baking since she was three, studying for a masters in business.
When she's not buried under books, she's getting muddy with dogs.
Miley, Smiley Ruby and Troublesome.
Tiggy.
Oh, Tiggy.
To bring the hazelnut flavor to her coffee cakes, she'll add chopped nuts to both her caramel filling and highly caffeinated sponge.
Have you practiced this?
Yeah.
What did your friends think of it?
Everyone has different tastes, I'll say that.
You can get friends anywhere.
Yeah, exactly.
This is a massive risk.
Ribs isn't the only baker adding a kick to their cake.
Chilli powder is there not to bring in the chilli, but helps bring in the flavours of the chocolate even further.
A keen dancer, software engineer Abdul likes to Lindy hop with girlfriend Christine.
Hello.
Born in Saudi Arabia but now living in London, he's not seen his family for over three years.
Oh.
Technical difficulties.
Containing raspberry jam and mascarpone between layers of chocolate and hazelnut sponge, Abduls sandwich cakes are dedicated to former friends.
I'm a huge lover of plants.
I have tons of them in my house.
I've killed a lot.
Unfortunately, I'm trying to make these cakes.
Pay tribute to those.
You're my favorite botanical serial killer.
You always hurt the ones you love.
Come on.
Thank you.
I called this a bite size of love.
Sandros bakes also come from the heart.
When I first met my partner.
Every time we saw each other, I would always give a white rose.
So I'm making, like, chocolate flower pots.
When Sandro, a fitness fanatic from East London, isn't hitting the gym, he works as a full time nanny.
I am the champion.
He'll fill his flower pots with a chocolate and orange sponge and a rich red wine ganache, from which delicate sugar roses will grow.
Are you a gym guy?
You look like you.
Are twice a day.
Once is not enough.
I do know because I'll do like weights.
And then I'll do cardio.
Same.
Can you tell?
I do weights in a graveyard.
The old bones.
Oh.
Yeah.
Forget cardio.
I haven't got a heart.
Yeah.
And it seems love is in the air.
These are many Persian love cakes.
We've got a large Persian community in our church, so it's a tribute to their faith and their friendship.
Kevin lives in Lanarkshire, Scotland with his wife Rachel and their dog Judy.
A talented musician, he not only plays the clarinet, flute and saxophone professionally, but he teaches too.
Nice one.
Kevin's love cakes are full of Persian flavour, with rose Swiss meringue buttercream sandwiched between layers of pistachio, almond and cardamom.
Sponge.
The sponge is going to have blitzed pistachio nuts, but I'm not going to blitz them right down.
I still want them to be a bit of texture and a bit of crunch.
I'm using 120g of pistachios.
May Sams also chosen to go all out with her nutty sponge.
I want to get as much flavour and texture in the cake as possible.
Born in Libya, this year's youngest baker, 18 year old design student, Mason lives in Manchester with her parents, two brothers and younger sister, Juri.
I'm going to copy your drawing.
What?
To help balance the sweetness of her pistachio packed sponge.
Mason will fill her sandwich cakes with raspberry jam and raspberry Swiss meringue buttercream.
In the practice.
It went really well, so I'm hoping that it'll turn out well this time.
You're the baby here.
Did you realize that?
I'm the youngest one, so pressure is on.
Key to creating delicious mini sandwich cakes.
Heavy on the coffee.
The judges will expect beautifully flavored soft sponge.
It's the blue eyed one that scares me.
It's just super intense.
It's like he's looking through my soul.
So disapprove.
And he looks at you like, ah!
I nearly forgot to put my eggs in.
Oh my goodness.
It's like something's missing here.
Swedish born Maxy, an architectural assistant from south east London, is passing on her passion for baking to daughters Tyra and Talia.
Okay, that's enough now.
She's giving her Eton Mess inspired cakes a tropical twist with mango and passion fruit coulis and mascarpone between layers of vanilla sponge.
You're from Sweden, but I can't hear the accent.
I've lived here for 21 years.
You speak.
Swedish as.
Well?
I do speak Swedish.
Are you?
I'm semi bilingual.
Oh.
Are you?
Mhm.
What languages do you speak?
English?
English.
And.
Well.
No I'm semi.
Oh semi.
Oh yeah.
Next time I've got a joke I'll put it in writing and send it to you in advance.
All right.
Ah.
Looks good.
It is going in.
The quicker the sponges hit the oven, the longer they'll have to cool.
11 minutes.
At 180.
Is there a time on this thing?
If the bakers attempt to cut and fill their layers of sponge while still warm, they'll be left with a crumbly, leaking mess.
Ah, crap.
I forgot to switch it on.
Sorry, it's not done yet.
I can tell by visual clues, i.e.
it's not brown.
Will is a charity director who lives in London with wife Alison and their three children Max, Verity and Louis.
That's going well.
Louis.
It's quite crumbly.
To cut through the sweetness of a salty, caramel swirled buttercream, and in a bid to stand out from the crowd, Wills cakes contain no less than three different types of ginger.
Who do you think is good?
Who are you scared of?
Uh, everybody.
I feel like the first one.
You're just finding your feet, aren't you?
New equipment, Paul, leering down on you.
It's not usually what happens, is it?
When you're at.
Home?
Basically.
Normally you just sit at home.
You haven't got a sort of tipsy posh woman and a bronze man staring at you.
You don't know where I live, do you?
All right, guys, I know you're new here, so basically, the way things work in this tent, if you want to know how long you got left, you have to give us each a fiver.
Oh, well, it was worth a try.
You've got an hour left.
An hour?
Is that good or bad?
It's bad for me.
I'm not feeling confident about my meringues cos these have to go in for an hour.
Oh, that's the timer for my cakes.
Ooh, they have risen very well.
More than I thought.
The difference between perfectly baked, moist sponge.
Oh.
It's done.
And a dry, dense disaster.
Oh, my.
Can be a matter of moments.
It should be cooked.
You get the absolute fear.
These are sticky toffee pudding sponges.
Bit alarmed at one edge have sunk.
Don't know how that happened, but I think it's okay.
It's like the famous last words, isn't it?
Originally from Glasgow, James, a nuclear scientist, has been baking since he was five years old.
It's a passion matched only by his love of 80s horror films.
That's incredible.
He'll add warmth to his sticky toffee apple sandwich cakes with ginger in his apple jam and nutmeg in his buttercream.
Explain the colour of the kilt then.
Is it family?
So it's actually the kilt I wore for my graduation.
Pants or no.
Pants?
Yeah, that's for you to find out, isn't it?
That's an invitation.
While there, sponge is cool.
I have a wee apple jam going.
The bakers turn their attention to fillings.
This is hazelnut caramel.
But I'm a wee bit concerned because it's a bit runny.
I probably put too much butter in.
I'm making Italian meringue buttercream.
They're technically complicated version of buttercream.
But Will's not the only one trying to impress with his ambitious icing.
Struggling to cut this butter.
The buttercream is flavoured with rose.
I know that rose can be a really overpowering flavour, so it's just a whisper.
While Will, Mason and Kevin attempt to sweeten up the judges.
Nice dozy doats and dozy doats.
Carol's gone sour.
Just make me lemon curd.
I don't put that much sugar in because I want it nice and tart.
West country born and bred.
Carol, a supermarket cashier, lives in Dorset with husband Michael.
A keen gardener.
She's affectionately known as compost Carol.
Yeah, a nice bit of root.
As well as her curd filling.
She'll add lemon juice to her buttercream and zest to her lemon and poppy seed sponge.
I'm a little bit of a classic bakery.
The carrot cakes and your lemon drizzles.
I'm not a big one for putting exotic ingredients in, you know.
But somewhere exotic is exactly where Dawn's heading.
I'm doing lime and tamarind spring cake.
Tamarind.
It's a slightly earthy flavour, but it's fruity at the same time.
And this bake, it's fairly traditional, but it's got a bit of a twist.
Dawn, a former project manager for Boris Johnson, lives in Bedfordshire, where she entertains granddaughter Emmie with her hand-modeled sugar figurines.
Mr.
Eggington, do you like him?
Yes.
To complement her tamarind jelly filling, she'll add coconut to her sponge and create a coconut marzipan topping.
You worked for Boris Johnson?
Not directly.
Did you get to meet him?
Yeah.
His hair was a bit like yours.
I know, wasn't it?
Yeah.
And his face was a bit like mine.
There you go.
We're like a hybrid.
Well.
Put us together and you have Boris Johnson.
How about that?
Yeah.
Dawn isn't the only baker bringing a taste of the tropics.
I am making Malaysian cake, which is based on pandan flavouring.
It is very aromatic.
People call it Asian vanilla.
Malaysian born Kabira lives in London, where she works in cardiovascular research.
Comes after a hard day in the lab.
She likes to relax gaming online with boyfriend Bradley.
Oh, headshot.
Oh, I got Headshotted.
Kabira will flavor her sponge and coconut custard with pandan and add caramel to both her mousse and decorations.
Traditional Malaysian sweets known as ondeh ondeh.
I'm going to make a caramel bomb.
When you bite into it, the caramel just bursts out.
You're gonna blow the judges heads off.
I love.
This.
Good luck, good luck.
This sounds amazing.
Thank you.
Anyone who tries to bomb these two is amazing in my book.
But Shabir, as caramel bombs aren't the only bake that should probably come with a safety warning.
I'm soaking my sponges with Polish cherry liqueur.
What I'm making today will be a Polish inspired bake which is vietka.
Janusz is a PA from Brighton, where he lives with boyfriend Simon and sausage dog Nigel.
He learned many of his Polish recipes from mum Elisha, who taught him and his sister to bake.
Filled with pistachio cream and cherries.
Hilltop his boozy zitka with a layer of rich chocolate ganache.
It's like a Polish black forest.
That's cherries soaked in booze.
Thinking of you.
Good.
Thank you.
You've done your homework.
I am glad to hear this.
Sounds absolutely delicious.
This is my kind of bike.
Good luck, good luck.
I want to do the time.
It's my.
Turn.
No, it's my turn.
Let me do the time.
I'm doing the time.
Call.
All right.
Fine.
You do the time call.
Bakers, you have half an hour left.
Ooh.
This sponge is done.
But my Italian meringue split for reasons I don't understand.
So I'm going to make it again.
But Italian meringue buttercream takes half an hour, so it's slightly worrying.
I'm about to start cutting out the cakes.
No matter whether they've baked large trays of sponge.
I'm just going to make small circles.
Or individual portions.
The judges will expect every slice of the bakers sandwich cakes to be uniform and neat.
The tubs will be cut off.
They all will be even size ruler.
I mean, most people wouldn't care, but the judges aren't most people.
The perfect slices.
It's very soft cake, so I need to be careful.
Require a cool sponge.
Oh, it's gone all crumbly.
I think I cut them whilst it was still a bit warm.
Now they're gonna need plenty of cherry vodka.
I've got my big guns here.
Drizzle some more pandan flavorings.
Oh my God.
Hopefully, with the help of buttercream, I managed to hide it.
did.
But there's a flaw in Mason's plan.
The buttercream has curdled.
Yeah.
It'll take some time to fix it.
How long have we got left?
Bakers, you have 15 minutes left.
Oh.
15 minutes.
Oh, my gosh, I'm gonna start assembling.
You'll make it.
We have to.
Ah! This caramel is starting to melt.
At home, I wouldn't care if the caramel was over the edge.
And now you're like.
Ah!
Now custard.
This is red wine ganache.
Proper.
Strong.
Finally seeing some Swiss meringue buttercream.
While Mason's filling comes together at last.
That was a nightmare.
A nightmare.
Pulled it off.
It's done it again.
For the second time.
Wills has split.
Ah!
I need to make buttercream.
How do I make buttercream?
Butter.
Sugar?
Yeah.
Decoration time making these fiddly little buggers.
So I'm just making the caramel for the wee candles.
You're a nuclear scientist, is that right?
Yeah.
This is a bit of a comedown for you, isn't it?
I mean.
Haven't you got more important things to be doing?
Making cakes is vastly more exciting.
These are cacao nibs.
It's the soil.
Hello, petal.
Hello.
I was talking to the.
Bakers, you have five minutes left.
Tight, tight tight, tight.
Get going.
I gotta get going.
Gotta decorate the top.
Add my fruits on.
Terrified.
Start away and get this done on time.
It's looking rubbish.
Think, William.
Calm yourself down, mate.
I feel like I shouldn't be this calm.
I just wonder what's gone wrong.
I'm just very carefully trying to put the coconut topping on.
I kind of wish the buttercream was a tiny bit better.
Oh, this is not good.
They're just sliding.
What a frigging nightmare.
Finishing touches.
Flavor wise should be good, but look wise.
100% not happy with it.
It's not perfect, but I do like it, I don't know.
These look amazing.
This is your Persian business, right?
Yes.
Have you been to Persia?
Uh, no.
Maybe one day.
We'll go together.
Yeah.
Are you free on the 14th?
14th of what I've got.
I've got to do a time call.
Goodbye.
Bakers, you have one minute left.
Oh my God.
60s.
Kids, you can do this.
I'm gonna try as many cactuses as possible.
A very rushed nutmeg job.
I'm just trying to do whatever I can do right now.
Don't collapse.
Bakers.
No.
Your time is up.
Oh.
Please step away from your mini sandwich cakes.
Well done, well done.
High ten.
That was a good high ten as well.
There's Margaret, there's many.
There's Maureen.
That's so cute.
Look at.
This.
Janusz, those are so neat.
It's rubbish.
Uh.
For the very first time, our 12 new bakers and their mini sandwich cakes are about to face the judgment of Paul and Prue.
Hello, Maxie.
Hiya.
In your world, mini is a curious thing.
That's huge.
Let's have a look at these monsters.
You've got it all over your fingers.
I can't take them anywhere.
You know, I've got mess in the title, so.
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
The cake's quite dry.
Is it dry?
You probably could have done with slightly less bake on that.
Yeah.
However, there's nothing wrong with passion fruit sponge and a meringue.
The combination of flavours is beautiful.
Well done, well done.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you.
Oh my goodness.
The pipework.
That's just like a blob.
What is that?
Who knows at this point?
That taste is like.
Mm.
Beautiful.
Absolutely sticky toffee pudding.
But better because it's got ginger.
So we figured out you can bake, but you need to concentrate on some of the detail.
I think they look great.
Love the decoration on the top.
So cute.
And I love the colors.
They're absolutely classic flavors.
Nicely balanced.
Yeah.
There's enough lemon in there because you're getting it through the curd as well, which is nice and sharp.
What's not to like?
Thank you.
They look very good.
Pretty consistent.
The rose is perfect.
The cake itself is a bit heavy.
You've got too much in there which will pull all the moisture from the cake.
So it's very, very dry.
Okay.
They don't look wonderful, do they?
No, they're falling apart.
I cut it whilst it was still warm inside. Fatal crumbling a bit.
The sponge is delicious and the Swiss meringue is lovely.
Could it have been sharper?
Could have had more raspberry in there.
I don't think there's anything wrong with the flavours.
It just looks a mess.
They do look amazing.
I love the colour.
I love the pot.
I love the soil.
I just hope inside tastes as good as it looks.
I mean, that is really clever to get all that in there.
The flavours are really punchy.
The red wine ganache works beautifully well with the raspberry.
Oh, it's rich and indulgent.
Well done.
Thank you.
At first glance, you think absolutely delightful.
If you look closely, there are a few problems on there.
They're a bit wibbly.
The timing works really well.
Coconut works beautifully well with it.
Overall, it's a really nice cake.
And it's original.
Good.
Well done.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Nice one.
Abdul, I think it looks absolutely delicious.
Thank you.
It's almost an illusion, which I quite like.
It does look like a garden.
Mm.
It's very light.
A little kick of chilli.
You get a little acidity.
I think the raspberry in there is a beautiful flavour.
I love the hazelnut as well.
Thank you.
I'm impressed.
Abdul.
Lovely.
Well done.
That went better than I thought, actually.
Thank you.
They could be neater.
Yes.
Love the colours, though.
They're vibrant and in your face.
Get the flavors in there.
Coming from the panda and the caramel and the coconut is delicious.
It's such an interesting thing to do.
A set custard on top of a cake.
Gooey and unctuous.
And not too sweet.
Yeah, okay.
It's bomb.
Time.
Can I nick a sugar bomb?
Yes.
Feel free.
That's amazing.
It's not too sweet.
Actually, I was expecting it to be.
But you do get the burst of sugar.
Look at me.
I'll have you two out of a job here.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
I liked it.
I mean, that counts for nothing, but I liked it.
It looks like your caramel was a bit runny.
Did you mean the caramel to run down the sides?
No.
I spent ages trying to get the caramel perfect.
And then it went.
It was enough coffee in there to keep you awake at night.
Mhm.
The other flavours are coming through, are not strong enough to compete with it.
And the ganache is too hard.
You're neat enough.
I can see that.
Just be careful about your flavors.
It's a bit messy.
My buttercream didn't go to plan twice.
The curse of the tent.
Feel the heart rate going up. Yeah.
Well, I think it's a bit
disappointing.
It's a bit bland.
There's ginger, but not enough.
There's a caramel undertone, but it's got no hero in there, which is what you need.
Besides that.
Brilliant.
Never mind.
Will.
That looks amazing.
It's neat as a pin.
Just has to taste good now.
Oh it's lovely.
Sponge.
Very light.
And boozy.
Yes, that's how I like them.
For me, that's perfect.
It is very boozy.
I think you've got too much booze.
That's the overwhelming flavour.
Texturally, it's perfect.
It really is.
It's got a problem here, isn't it?
Because I think booze is perfect.
Well done.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
They're now stumbling.
Back.
Out of the tent.
I'm happy that it went well.
There was a lot of booze in my cake because even when I'm eating it, I'm thinking that's wrong.
They like it.
They like my ondeh ondeh.
It is very nice when people say your food is good.
It's interesting to have a disaster in your first challenge.
Not my finest moment.
I think it's fair to say.
Each week, the bakers will face a mystery.
Second challenge veiled by gingham.
Hello, bakers.
Welcome back to the tent.
It's time for your first ever technical challenge.
And your technical challenge today has been set for you by baby Paul.
Oh.
Paul.
Any words of advice?
It's a classic.
Concentrate on your sponge.
Well, as ever, this task is judged blind.
So we ask Paul and Prue to leave the tent where they are going to be cryogenically frozen.
Wrap up warm kids.
So Paul would like you to produce a red velvet cake.
Oh.
Your All-American layered cake should make a big impression on both the eyes and the palate.
I love impressions, Matt's good at impressions.
Fact.
He does an amazing Paul. God.
Do you?
Paul.
You're a good baker.
You're a good baker, too.
All right.
I mean, if you cover your eyes, it's like he's back in the tent.
Uncanny.
Your classic cake should consist of six tender, moist, crimson red sponges sandwiching a smooth, fluffy cream cheese icing.
Sprinkled with red crumbs to give it that red velvet finish.
You have two hours until we defrost Paul and Prue.
On your marks.
Get set.
Bake.
Obviously, my first challenge was a disaster, so I'm stressed.
It's like anxiety.
In the technical challenge.
The bakers are all given the same basic recipe.
This is very sentimental.
This is the first cake I ever made.
I normally do a red velvet cake, but that's the curse in it.
You're like, yeah, I know how to do that.
And then this is the one that you don't.
I've never made one before.
Paul.
Red velvet cake for our first technical.
Why have you gone for that?
The advantage is everybody will know it.
It's quite a light, chocolatey cake with the use of vinegar and buttermilk blended with bicarb.
There's your raisin agent.
And actually, there's the flavour.
It has a very distinctive tang to it.
Obviously there's coloring to give it that beautiful, vibrant red inside.
Wow.
We haven't told the bakers how much food coloring.
Adding too much will make the cake far too dark.
And the proportion of cream cheese is much higher than you'd have in most sponges.
Yeah, it's a big cake.
We want height.
So the thickness of cream cheese is critical.
It's lovely.
I can't wait to see what they're going to turn out like.
What I'm not looking forward to is trying 12 red velvet cakes.
You're gonna have to stretch me out of there.
The first instruction is make the red velvet batter.
No hints as to how good.
What do we.
Do?
Luckily, I've got it all in here.
I'm mixing my butter and sugar.
Screaming up.
That's what I want.
Now I'm gonna add the eggs, the buttermilk, flour, cocoa and vinegar.
Why are you putting vinegar in it?
Like, what's that about?
Why would you ever put vinegar in a cake?
It's a bit of a chemical reaction.
Like Diana Ross sang that.
Combining vinegar, buttermilk and bicarbonate of soda creates the bubbles crucial to producing a light sponge.
So I'll chuck in a bunch now.
But timing is everything.
You've got to add the bicarb just before you put it in the oven, because it doesn't last very long.
I'm just going to wing it.
There's not really a method.
How red to make it is the question.
Crimson was the directive.
What is crimson mean?
Does it mean
light red?
Hers is a bit redder than yours.
Look, this is true.
You could add a bit more.
I mean, I don't ask me.
I've got no clue what I'm doing.
But then I'll blame you.
I won't care.
You know.
That.
Right?
Come on then, babies.
It just says bake at your leisure, however long you want.
Ah, sugar.
Those are being baked for as long as it takes.
I think.
25 minutes.
They're not very big, so I might give them, like 13 minutes, and then I'll see how they're doing.
What are you.
Doing?
Who knows?
Sort of clattering an adventure.
I'm just.
I'm just flinging stuff.
You've made a red velvet cake before.
I have, but not for about 30 years when my kids were little.
I have to go back into.
The yeah, the trouble is, I was probably under the influence of alcohol.
For red velvet cake.
It's very personal for me.
Before I left Malaysia, my friends, we all sit down together for four of us, having a very nice red velvet cake.
So I just made the last cake that I had with my friends.
Without them, I will never discover my hidden talent to bake.
Bakers, you are halfway through.
I don't want to put any pressure on you guys, but we're going to take the best red velvet cake with the aid of a sewing machine.
I'm going to turn it into skimpy briefs for me and Matt.
If I fail to see why that's funny.
Make the cream cheese frosting.
There's no recipe.
Just making it.
I'm just gonna mix my cream cheese and mascarpone together, then add the double cream and then whip it.
It should be fluffy.
Safe.
Yeah.
But the bakers must whip with caution over whip, and their frosting will become a runny mess.
I didn't get this tick, man.
Because it's not going to settle.
Hoo boy.
That is liquid.
It's got to be like this where it can lift and it's made it gloss.
Yeah.
This is, like, perfect cream cheese here.
I'm gonna take a little bit longer.
So it's a waiting game.
They're taking forever to bake.
Taking so long.
It's giving me anxiety.
Just waiting.
Kevin, does it annoy you that there's another Scottish person in here?
Because it annoys me.
And I'm not even Scottish.
He's wearing a kilt and kicking it out.
Scottish to me.
He has.
Out scotched you, hasn't.
He?
Yeah.
Do you know him?
I assume everyone in Scotland knows each other.
We do come from the same county.
Yeah.
We did actually have the same saxophone and clarinet teacher.
There you go.
Hi, Andy.
How are you doing?
Haven't they done well?
You've taught them so well.
They're baking cakes instead.
I don't know.
No, he ain't ready.
This cake hasn't ready yet.
I'm worried.
I opened the oven.
They'll go.
All right.
Mine have to be done, though.
Oh.
Someone's ready.
Oh, this is not good.
They've sunk.
Ah, nightmare.
The cake just wasn't cooked long enough.
Change of temperature from the oven to the cold heater.
I'm just gonna have to go with it.
Bakers, you have half an hour left.
Also, bakers, remember, as hard as it is to make a red velvet cake, I've actually made a red velvet coat.
Come on then, babies.
My sponges are ready.
Smooth.
I'm very pleased.
Oh, yeah.
I'm happy with that.
Just calm down my nerves.
Mason is slowly coming back.
That looks weird.
I don't know whether it's moist or undercooked.
Yeah, I was gonna high five you, but I've seen your palms there to read?
Good luck!
Slice each sponge in half horizontally, remove the bowl of icing from the fridge and put it together.
To achieve the height the judges expect.
Their frosting must be the perfect consistency.
It's a bit liquidy, I think.
And generously applied.
I'm trying to make proper even layers.
I just want to try to get the height like a proper big one.
To decorate neatly coat the cake.
I would rather do something different.
I'm going for a semi-naked look.
Definitely for this one.
You know you can go for that distressed look.
A sprinkle of the leftover crumbs around the bottom edge.
They're going to be fairly scant crumbs.
Type eight rosette.
Nearly there.
My icing is melting.
Oh man.
It will be a blob of rosette.
Going mad with piping trying to show off.
I want this presentation to be like, you know, like up there.
Bakers, you have one minute left.
Crumbs.
All.
Blimey.
It isn't, it isn't it.
Isn't it isn't it isn't.
It isn't scary.
Focus.
Bakers.
Your time is up.
Oh, this is not good.
That's not good.
Breathe.
This is the height that I want
done.
Well, I can see that everyone is going for a completely different style.
You cannot tell at the moment who has the right idea.
That distressed look is a decision I may well regret.
Oh, this is getting me like angels.
Decorations.
Immaculate.
It's really sunk.
I'm so annoyed.
Bakers, please bring your velvet cakes down to the tablecloth.
Put them behind your photograph.
The gingham altar of doom.
Oh, man, my icing is melting.
Oh, I don't know.
Joe.
I'm really intrigued by the different heights.
Yeah.
Sabera. Yours is well.
Tall Paul and Prue are expecting 12 tall red velvet cakes coated in fluffy cream cheese frosting and decorated with a sprinkling of crumbs.
They have no idea whose is whose.
Oh, God.
Okay.
Starting over here.
It is smooth, but it's not that tall, is it?
That's nicely.
Not much cream cheese filling in there, is it?
Cream cheese should be almost equal to the cake to keep that height.
Tastes good.
Soft with a little bit of tartness.
Moving on to number two.
Piping is good.
But the crumb on the outside, it's too thick.
The flavors are right.
It's only got the tang to it.
Right over here.
This one's really attractive.
Mhm.
But I think the cake is slightly undercooked.
And I also think there's quite a lot of red in this one.
Yeah, it's very red.
You asked for crimson.
It's the wrong shade of crimson, Matt.
All right, back off.
Okay.
Moving on.
Not much height to.
It needs to be a bit higher.
And it's not very light.
It's solid.
That's a little bit claggy.
Feels slightly underdone.
Right.
Now.
This one's almost a naked cake around the outside, isn't it?
Very little cream cheese.
But sponge is nicely risen.
Yeah,
the sponge is light and tangy.
So we have this one.
It's quite original decoration.
Looks like a wedding hat.
I don't like that.
Cream cheese should have been put in the layers.
That's probably lost quite a bit of height through that.
Sponges are all sponges, right?
Just not what we wanted.
Right?
This one over here, it's lost its definition.
Rather flat rosettes.
But it's only got the tang to it.
Mm.
Nice flavor.
Okay.
Moving on.
Could be a bit straighter.
Yes, it's a bit on the lean.
But sponges are right.
You get that lightness.
This is a good cake.
This one's got much too much crumb on the bottom.
Decoration doesn't look great.
Sponge.
It's actually not that bad.
I just think it's lighter seeing that a little bit neater throughout.
Right.
This one.
Big layers of sponge.
The sponge is light.
But the rosettes sunk all over the place.
I do hope that's as good on the inside as it looks on the outside.
Height of the cake is good.
The definition is.
This is what we were looking for when it came to the crumb.
That light dusting.
It's got to be good inside.
It better be good inside.
Nice layers.
There is a lot of cream cheese there.
That is very nice.
That's it.
Should we go home now?
Okay, moving onto this one a little bit.
Too much on the crumb.
It's neat though,
and I do like those sponges.
I've got nice zing.
Absolutely.
Paul and Prue will now rank the red velvet cakes from 12th to first place.
In 12th place.
This one.
Who's that?
James.
We didn't like the decoration much, and there's not quite enough cream in the middle.
In 11th, we have Rebs basically very claggy.
In 10th place.
This one.
Maxi, it was undercooked.
Ninth, we have this one.
Well, it's all over the place.
Fair enough.
Carol is eighth.
Janusz seventh.
Sixth Abdul Masum fifth.
Kevin is fourth and Dawn third.
We're getting close now.
In second place.
Who is this?
Sandra could be a tiny bit higher, but it's a really good cake.
Thank you.
So in first place, we have.
That's fantastic.
Thank you.
My heart just melts.
Thank you so much.
Well done.
Shapira.
If I'm upset, I'll cry.
If I'm happy, I'm crying.
I'm happy with second.
Yeah, second is kind of first, isn't it?
It wasn't the worst, but I know I've got a lot to do tomorrow.
It was a disaster.
Like, I just like I wasn't 12.
But there's still another big.
I will pick myself back up and make sure my cakes flippin well cooked this time.
Just one challenge remains before this year's first star.
Baker is crowned and the first person to leave the tent is revealed.
So what do we think of these new bakers?
Overall, the standard has been pretty good.
Yeah, but I think a few people, it got to them.
Rebs will is in trouble.
Mason.
She had a tough signature, didn't she?
Yeah.
So who's in line for Star Baker?
I think the likes of Abdul Janusz.
You know who else?
Sandra.
Sandra is amazing.
Sandra is technically tremendously good as well.
He's calming me down.
I'm not even in the competition.
And Shabbir is incredible.
That's a technical challenge.
It was actually better than mine.
I mean, it's not that hard to believe, is it?
Unbelievable.
When's the last time you baked porn?
70s.
Last week.
What did you bake?
Blueberry muffins.
Oh, lovely.
Nice.
As good as Shabir.
Is, I was like this.
Well done.
Hello, bakers.
It's time for your first ever showstopper challenge.
And today, the judges would love you to make a stunning 3D replica of your own home entirely out of cake.
Your showstopper should look like somewhere you have lived, which has special meaning to you.
It needs to be so good that Paul can live inside it for a week.
He's basically having his bathroom renovated.
He needs somewhere to crash.
You have four hours.
On your marks.
Get set.
Bake.
Oh, it's so quiet in here.
Concentration.
Doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Yesterday wasn't my day.
But today's going to be my day.
I want to just show them that I am a better baker than Claggy cake.
This is their first showstopper.
And it's a home bake.
A bake of their home.
It could be anything.
A cottage, a block of flats, a bungalow.
But I want detail.
You know, we want the pebbledash.
And we want the ivy floating up the sides.
We want the window frames.
Of course, the most important thing is that it's solid.
We don't want the roof blowing off.
We don't want the walls falling down.
We want to see 12 fabulous homes looking amazing and tasting even better.
Morning, dawn.
Good morning.
Morning.
Tell us all about your home bake.
So my home bake is my nans house.
Did you live in it?
I was born in it, actually.
So was my mum.
It's a three bed semi and it's pebbledashed.
Daum will recreate her nan's pebbledash from praline, while inside, apricot puree and German buttercream will be sandwiched between layers of delicate Genoese sponge.
So it's 12 layers.
Freestanding.
Interesting that you're using Genoese, which is notoriously quite a soft thing with 12 layers with heavy cakes.
Yep.
Interesting.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Dawn's not the only baker inspired by memories of their nan.
When I was younger, I would go there for Christmas.
It'll be like about 70 of us.
It was like my best childhood memories.
Sandro will build his grandparents home from strawberry sponge, which he'll soak in strawberry liqueur for some extra Christmas spirit.
We used to leave our Christmas parties with beanbags full of presents when we were younger.
Now I can barely get socks.
Just grandparents.
If you're listening to this.
I know.
Presents get worse as you.
Get older.
Yeah, they do get worse.
Socks.
I can't afford socks.
Is that what you're trying to say to me?
And it seems the festive cheer is spreading.
I'm using polish, ginger, spices and oranges in my chocolate cake.
Because what is the better time to go and visit your mum than Christmas?
Janusz spent many a happy Christmas in Poland and it's his mum's flat he'll recreate, from rich chocolate sponge and spiced orange buttercream, colourfully decorated to bring her garden balcony to life.
It was a very sad block of flats, but I could always tell where my mum is because it was the only balcony where you could actually see flowers.
So this is the final cake mix.
I couldn't actually get a bowl big enough.
I think it's a two spoon job.
Building a showstopper this big.
In total there is five kilograms of butter.
I mean, I'm making a house, right?
Requires a sponge that not only tastes great.
I'm adding soy sauce instead of salt.
It makes it more rich umami flavor.
But it's sturdy enough to support the weight of their construction.
Come on.
This is a Madeira cake, which is a proper structural cake.
I'm not particularly concerned about the sponge.
It's pretty stable.
It's a banana cake.
It's my mum's recipe that I've tweaked a little.
With a roof and windows built from biscuit.
Kevin's childhood home will contain fresh banana and maple buttercream between layers of his mum's pecan packed banana bread.
I haven't chopped them too finely because I reckon that would actually dry out the sponge.
And
I do like a bit of texture.
I do like.
Nice big nuts.
This is coffee and walnut.
Who doesn't like coffee and walnut unless you don't like coffee or are allergic to nuts?
I am making a replica of my little bungalow.
Carol will build her beloved bungalow from another of her favourite classic cake recipes, coffee and walnut.
But instead of adding real coffee to her buttercream and sponge, she's opted for a retro replacement.
It's chicory.
It's when you couldn't get coffee.
I think maybe when the war was on.
I'm not sure.
You smell it, can't you?
That'll put hairs on your chest.
Okay.
Going in with so much cake to bake.
All done.
And the sponges are ready to go to the oven.
The quicker they're sponges.
Hit the heat.
Off you go.
The more time they'll have to cool and cut them.
I'm trying to make them not too thick because then they cook quicker and cool quicker.
Any attempt to build their homes from warm sponge will result in a subsidence nightmare.
I'll remember to set the timer today.
But Will's making life doubly difficult for himself.
I'm also making a chocolate cake.
It's slightly drier, which I think is good for the structure.
After a disappointing first day, Will's looking to impress by constructing his old north London flat from two sponges, one chocolate and one orange, with architectural details made from gingerbread.
So you've got gingerbread, you've got sponge, you've got orange.
Lot to do.
Hopefully you get away with it at the time.
Thank you.
I know.
Just a stone's throw away in southeast London is the flat where Maxie grew up.
It's my mum's block where I started baking.
Flavours are inspired by a family favourite, which is my mum's apple and berry crumble.
Maxie will spread her mum's famous apple and berry compote, along with a crumble topping between layers of cinnamon sponge.
Are you enjoying your time here?
I am, I just, you know, I get a bit stressed sometimes.
Who are you scared of more Prue or Paul?
Paul has got a tough exterior, like a crusty roll.
He's like a crusty bat, but when you break him open, he's all soft inside.
And he's good.
You know, a little bit of butter toasted.
So
this has gone weird, isn't it?
This?
No.
This conversation.
How are you looking, cakes?
I just want to double check if it's cooked.
Yep.
Shouldn't be too dry, huh?
I'm gonna take my small sponges out of the oven.
They seem to be all ready.
I hope it's cooked.
God.
I don't want to over bake it.
I just want it to be perfect.
So I'm going to let the sponges cool for as long as I can.
I know my oven wasn't on in hell.
My oven wasn't on for the past 40 minutes.
If Abdul can bake his sponges in time, he'll build his grandparents home in Pakistan with mango and saffron jam sandwiched between layers of masala chai.
Spiced sponge cooling time and everything is now challenging because I've lost about 40 minutes.
But keep going, keep going and trying, right?
Shabir is also hoping to tempt the judges with a cuppa milk.
Tea is something we drink all the time in Malaysia.
And in a bid for top spot.
Kirsty.
Her cake contains not just one but two types of tea.
Milk tea is the main flavour that I want to bring in.
and match our complement.
Milk tea filled with strawberry and cinnamon jam and matcha buttercream, Shibuya's Milk Tea sponges will form the childhood home and tropical garden she loved to play in growing up.
I can't imagine where you live.
So somewhere fantastical in a shoe, a golden shoe.
I live in a village, very small little house with coconut tree around it, so we usually try to climb the coconut because we thought if monkey could do it, we also could do it.
I can tell this is going to be my favorite chat of the day already.
In theory, this is done.
As world's final sponge exits the oven.
There we go.
Oh boy.
Closely followed by Abdul's.
It's okay, it's okay.
It landed the right side up.
Yes.
Today is not my day.
Is it.
Cold?
Cold, cold.
The rest of the bakers are ready to begin building.
Their cooled enough to start stacking.
And of course.
The soak I'm going to be fairly generous with this.
Want it to be perfection?
This is strawberries and cream liqueur.
I'm going to add all of it.
Grown up cake.
But Sandro's grown up cake won't be drinking alone.
Plenty of coconut rum.
Whoa! That was hot.
During lockdown because obviously we couldn't go anywhere.
Me and my parents would just have, like, a cocktail night.
So this is one of the ones that went down a treat with a pina colada.
Rebs plans to bring party vibes to her house with flambed, pineapple rings and rum buttercream sandwiched between layers of a rum soaked coconut sponge.
It's really important for me to get the sponge right today because I didn't cook mine sponge properly yesterday.
Oh my goodness.
You're joking.
My cake's not fully done.
But Rebs party.
They're not fully cooked.
Might be off.
Um, I don't know what I'm going to do.
Um,
I just need a minute to myself.
I feel like I'm gonna be sick.
You know, it was your turn to do the time call.
And then I just spoke over you.
It was really out of order, so I won't ever do that again.
So go on.
You do the time.
Really?
Yeah.
This is your.
Time.
No, no, no.
This one.
This one's.
Yours.
You're giving me your time.
I'm giving you my time.
Bakers, you are halfway through.
Sorry, I forgot, I forgot.
I would like to be carving cakes by now, but I've still got gingerbread to make.
I think I'm going to struggle with time.
And Will's not the only one struggling.
My sponge.
They've just not really fully cooked.
I don't know why.
But Rebs has a cunning plan to get back on track.
This one's okay.
I'm just going to take a ring a cake from here and put it in.
Look, you'd never know.
It's fine, it's fine.
I'm not going to panic.
Why would I panic?
Panic is for losers
constructing now.
So we're layering up.
This is going in now.
My crumble.
Kevin's just bashing.
Stuff.
Yeah, this wasn't even part of the recipe.
Who are you imagining that is Paul or Peru?
Well, what one is it?
The same color.
It's Paul, isn't it?
What is that?
It's about Scotch.
Butterscotch.
That's what he takes.
It's a tanning salon.
I want to look like this.
Carol, look at this color.
Oh, without any food coloring.
This is my childhood house back home in Libya.
Taking inspiration from her favorite lemon tree growing up, Maisam will fill her lemon sponge with blueberry jam and add colorful decoration to give the house the finish Paul and Prue expect.
If I just speed up a little bit, then I can give them that finesse that they want.
Oh no.
Small explosion.
James two has been inspired by a childhood memory.
My dad used to have a cottage up in Loch Fyne.
It's the first place I remember getting terrified.
We watched Dracula, and while we were watching it, my dad wandered by with an axe outside of the door.
It was like a 4D experience.
James is frightfully tasty.
Cottage will contain orange curd and orange blossom buttercream spread between six thick layers of orange and cardamom sponge.
It's oozing a tiny bit, but surprisingly okay because it is quite a lot of weight on top.
But we'll find out, I guess.
Bakers, you have 30 minutes.
Oh.
Definitely behind.
While Will and Abdul are still constructing their homes.
My plan is to disassemble this and then as much as I can decor.
I'll try for the rest of the bakers.
It's a nail biting race to the finish.
I'm trying to be mean.
I was over generous with the fillings, so I skipped a layer.
The only person that will notice is Paul.
I'm sure he'll count them all.
This is sugar fondant.
Samuel, is this easy to brick?
A house roof under construction.
My dad was a roofer as well.
Irony.
What can I smell?
Yeah, I smell burning.
It's not me, is it?
A little bit overdone.
I love a.
Dashing.
I used to get told off when I was a little girl cos we.
Went.
Off.
Yes.
I feel like this is going to tap into Paul's childhood as well.
He will lie.
He will identify with.
People who have a clue.
She won't know what it is.
If you haven't got a maze around your house, she won't understand.
Or a moat.
Got a gate?
The brickwork around the cottage.
I wanted to show the sort of higgledy piggledy ness of it.
Time is the limiting factor right now.
I'm going to have to leave out a lot of things, I think.
What are you going to do with that?
I'll probably eat it later.
Will you?
Yeah.
And what are you going to do with these?
One of the main issues is the misuse of disused tissues.
Embarrassing.
Bakers, you have five minutes left.
The stress.
Is real.
Come on.
I have to give Christmas now.
Far. The more detail, the better.
Nearly there.
But I'm piping clouds out of Italian meringue.
What is happening here?
Ah, it looks terrible.
Taxi! You're not on your own.
I need another couple of windows on it.
My hands are shaking.
Can't stop, can't stop.
Wow.
It's not what you think.
No.
What is.
It?
Coconut tree.
So I'm making the truck.
Oh, right.
Okay.
Yeah.
I'm trying to use this burfi to make sheep's. I can't watch you do that.
Sorry.
It brings back too many memories.
I hope it's a good one.
Bakers, you have one minute left.
This buttercream is split.
Don't even look like squares.
This is better than the red velvet cake.
It's a step in the right direction.
There's just some shimmer.
Bakers, your time is up.
Please step away from your fate. I feel so mean.
What kind of showstopper is this?
It's not as I pictured it.
That is so, so good.
It looks incredible.
It's not as neat as I'd like, but it looks like my house, which is a bonus.
I just don't want to go home.
It's time to judge the showstopping home bakes.
Rebs, would you like to bring your showstopper up, please?
Precious.
Happy.
Oh.
There's one more thing I need to get.
So, I don't know if you've ever been to Northern Ireland, but it's constantly raining, so you have to have a bit of coconut rum, rain.
I like the idea of coconut rum rain.
I know.
Nice.
It does remind me of a very rural cottage.
It's very good.
And the detail is lovely.
Now, this is basically a pina colada cake, isn't it?
Yeah.
Coconut and vanilla sponge, pineapple curd and flambed.
Pineapple slices with coconut and rum buttercream.
Mm.
I love the flavour.
The pineapple comes through.
Coconut comes through.
It is overbaked the sponge.
Not by much.
But overall I think a it looks great.
B the flavours came through beautifully.
Well done.
Raj. I can't breathe.
Should we takeaway?
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Quit while you're.
Ahead.
Thank you so much.
I'm going to take the tablecloth.
Well done.
Thank you.
I'm going to.
Cry.
What are the windows?
Sugar cookie filled with butterscotch.
Did you mean to burn them?
I didn't mean to.
The banana cake itself is delicious.
My only thing is cut your pecans up more.
They're too big.
It's a really good cake.
Well done.
It's beautifully neat, Carol.
And the piping is beautiful.
Look at that.
I love the pots all around the outside.
It's coffee and walnut with coffee buttercream.
It's quite powerful.
That coffee add a good glug.
It's really powerful.
I've never had a coffee cake that strong before.
Nor me.
Coffee's actually burning.
That's fascinating.
Wow.
You've blown Paul's mind.
Lots of skills showing off here.
You're obviously very good at piping.
Thank you.
So much.
Buttercream I know.
It's very claggy.
Especially that middle layer, which is really compressed.
I think it's the weight.
There's so much buttercream on there.
The sponge just can't hold it.
It glues your mouth together, which at the moment might be a good thing for you, but the flavours are fantastic.
You obviously ran out of time.
The piping's a bit clumsy.
Let's have a look.
Oh wow.
I've never had a crumble in a cake before.
I think you've done a really good job.
The crumble with the compote, it's just fantastic.
I think it works really well.
Well done.
Thank you.
I was so worried.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Boo!
You've lost a lot of the detail on the house.
Yes.
Did you run out of time?
Unfortunately, my oven wasn't hot, which meant my cakes were delayed, so that basically pushed everything.
My sponge is masala chai and in between I have mascarpone frosting and mango jam.
The chai is delicious, carries really well inside the cake.
I think the bakes good as well.
I think it's absolutely delicious, but I would have liked more mango.
Okay, I'd just like to see more detail because I think inside tastes great.
It looks absolutely charming.
I love it, I like the pebbledash.
It's gone a bit wonky, but I'm thinking the house was wonky.
Subsidence.
Terrible.
Wow.
Oh, look at that.
It's Genoese sponge with apricot praline and vanilla buttercream inside.
How many layers?
It was supposed to be 12.
I'm going to be really honest and admit that there are 11.
It's really brave to make Genoa's so airy that it could get squashed easily, but it hasn't squashed at all.
That is a fantastic cake.
You've got texture coming from the praline, the apricot is lovely and it's got a bit of tartness to that as well, which really works.
The sponge is well baked, the buttercream works well.
Well done.
I like the whole look of it.
I think it's charming.
The detail in there is lovely.
So this has got a lot of interesting flavours in this, hasn't it?
It is milk tea sponge with strawberry jam and matcha buttercream.
It's nice.
I think your textures are beautiful.
The baking element is perfect.
Those sponges are delicious.
My issue is there's no hero flavour.
There's so many little things going on in there.
There's matcha, there's strawberry.
The tea flavour is not strong enough.
Oh my God.
I recognize that vlog now.
Really?
Yeah.
We live near each other.
That's brilliant.
So good.
You've overbaked everyone.
Ah.
I think the chocolate could have been a bit more punchy.
Love the orange.
But it comes down to the bake for me.
It's not perfectly decorated, is it?
It's a little bit clumsy.
Well, let's have a look, shall we?
It's lemon, which is inspired by the lemon trees in that house.
Mm.
It's quite dense.
That doesn't take away the fact that I actually love the flavour.
It is just a bit puddingy.
I mean, if I had that in a bowl with custard, I'd be in heaven.
But this is supposed to be cake.
I like the flavours.
Texture's all wrong.
Bit simple on the decoration.
Yes.
The decorations look quite sweet, but I expected that to be a lot more detailed than it is.
It's just a little bit simplistic.
What you don't know is his grandparents actually lived in a cake.
So it's actually very accurate.
Yeah.
Wow.
Look at that.
Well, there's lots of strawberries and cream.
Just bowl me over that.
There's too much alcohol in there.
Do you know?
Yeah.
Too much.
I thought I'd never hear me say this, but he's right.
Sponge is lovely and soft, but somehow, if you put booze in a filling, it's modified by the cake.
But if it's in the cake, it's everywhere.
I love it for the colour and the vibrancy.
The decoration and the pipe work.
You've done an amazing job.
This looks beautiful.
This area here.
I can see coming home to your mum's flat.
Must have been really good.
It is chocolate cake.
It contains soy sauce.
For the umami.
Correct.
And inside.
Christmas inspired buttercream.
It is utterly delicious.
Just the right amount of spice.
Very chocolatey.
The textures and the bakes all the way through are delicious.
I can't fault it.
It's excellent.
Thank you.
Well done.
It's a work of art.
Dallas has had.
Yeah.
That's
amazing feedback.
If I was named Star Baker, that in my heart would actually be, like winning the competition for me.
Because cake is my favorite.
They say the cake looks lovely, but it doesn't have a punchy flavor.
Yeah.
It's fair.
I know I made a booboo that way.
Could have been worse.
But you know, I still feel like I'm.
I'm languishing a little bit along the bottom.
I'm in danger.
To be honest, I don't know whether I've done enough to stay.
I'm very happy it went as well as it possibly could have done.
I just hope it's enough to be not bottom anymore.
Prue and Paul have made their decision.
It's going to be okay.
So.
I've got a great job this week of announcing the star Baker.
And this week's star baker is.
Janusz.
Wow.
Well, if it was up to me, I'd keep you all here and send one of the judges home.
Sadly, it isn't up to me.
And we do have to say goodbye to one of you, which feels very early, but the person who is leaving us is.
Its will.
Well, guys, you go and all knock it out of the park.
Honestly.
Well, you should just feel proud of yourself.
Well done will.
Thank you.
Dear.
Well done.
You know, somebody's got to go first.
And and obviously I'm disappointed, but I'm proud to have made it.
Yeah.
I'm all right.
I knew it was going to happen.
Conversations.
You know, there's obviously a lovely bunch of people I've met.
I've got an experience that I can definitely talk about and share.
Yeah, I'm proud of that.
Proud of that.
Bit better next week, please.
I need to be a lot neater, a lot neater.
Oh, I'm still here.
Oh, I literally I can't believe it.
I was constantly hearing my name next week.
I really want to impress the judges and also make myself proud as well.
Well done.
Janusz.
You absolute rock star.
A winning star baker on the cake week means everything to me.
And hopefully to you.
Are you crying?
I've cried so many times.
It's crazy.
I think my boyfriend would be really proud.
And he would say, you can make cake.
And I've told you, you can make cake.
Well done.
The first star, baby.
Thank you.
Hey, Honeybun.
I just wanted to tell you that I win star cake in the bake week.
No,
I win.
No!
Next time.
Goodbye.
It's biscuit.
Week.
Say a little prayer.
A signature illusion.
What could go wrong with a macaron?
Whoa!
Ah!
Everything could go wrong with a macaron.
A classical technical.
I don't know what that is.
That creates a buzz in the tent.
Squashed biscuits.
That's what my mom called them.
Well, where's your gob?
And the bakers face off
as they make showstopping masks.
Oh, I might cry.
I might cry.